Contact

Soerser Weg, 11A Aachen 52070 +491774050220 (Home) shubham.agrawal16@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/shubhamagrawal-25343870 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Compound Semiconductors Semiconductors Integrated Circuits (IC)

Languages

German (Limited Working)

Honors-Awards

Deutschlandstipendium scholarship

Shubham Agrawal

Pursuing MS in Micro- and Nanoelectronics | Student Assistant (HiWi) at RWTH Aachen University

Aachen-Mitte

Summary

I have always been fascinated by electronic gadgets, and how they make our work so easy. I love the way technology has changed this world. How a small thing such as a transistor can do wonders. I study something new every day and it surprises me every single time.

During my bachelor's, I studied electronics and communications. Subjects like Analog and digital system designs, Electronic Devices and Circuits, and VLSI design interested me the most. It was when I worked on the project "Voice-controlled Robocar" during my Summer Training in Embedded systems at TATA CMC when I really felt connected to the subject and its applications. During my Internship at DRDO, New Delhi, I came across compound semiconductors devices such as HEMTs and their fabrication. This was the time I decided to take my career forward and pursue MS in Micro- and Nanoelectronics to study more about the subject.

In my last year in Germany, I have learned about the developments, applications, and challenges in the fabrication of nanoelectronic devices. Solid State Devices, Compound Semiconductor, and Optical Communications were the major subjects of interest. My fondness towards these subjects earned me a good grade and a Deutschlandstipendium scholarship from Bildungsfonds der RWTH. Currently, I am working with the Chair of Integrated Digital Systems and Circuit Design on FPGAs.

I believe in hard work and maximum efforts. I am looking forward to building my career in Fabrication of semiconductor devices and Analog & Digital Design.

Experience

Chair of Integrated Digital Systems and Circuit Design, RWTH Aachen University
Student Assistant (HiWi)
June 2018 - Present (2 years 3 months)
Aachen, Germany

Study of Content Addressable Memories and their implementations using FPGA.

Defence Research and Development Organisation (DRDO) Summer Research Intern June 2017 - July 2017 (2 months)

New Delhi, India

- -Worked on Design and Fabrication of Monolithic Microwave Integrated Circuits.
- -Studied various Ferrite components and MEMs components.
- -Studied and Verified various reliability issues of GaN HEMTs.

Tata Consultancy Services Summer Trainee June 2016 - July 2016 (2 months) New Delhi, Indi

- -Worked on microprocessors such as 8051 and microcontrollers such as Atmega 32.
- -Learned programming language Embedded C to work on Kiel and AVR Studio 7.
- -Worked on the project, Voice controlled Robocar.

Education

RWTH Aachen University

Master of Science - MS, Micro- & Nanoelectronics · (2018 - 2021)

Maharaja Agrasen Institute Of Technology
Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Electronics and Communications
Engineering · (2014 - 2018)

Woodbine Modern School - India AISSCE (12th Standard) · (2011 - 2013)